American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIa. 1743-1806 APS.Archives.IIa APS.Archives.IIa
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to John Redman Coxe, Secretary of A.P.S, June 30, 1801; 7 1/4" x 9"; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    London, A.L.S: J.P. Auriol, secretary. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges set of A.P.S. Transactions; mentions Count Rumford.
  - American Philosophical Society to George Flake, July 10, 1801; 6 3/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan; receipted by Georg[e] Flake. Receipted bill for $12, for painting Rittenhouse Observatory.
  - Depositions in re indebtedness by George Turner to the American Philosophical Society, July 16, 1801; 15x9-1/4; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan and Jno. R. Smith. 4p.
  - Jno. R. Smith to [John] Vaughan, July 17, 1801; 5" x 7 7/8"; Smith, John R.
    1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipt for $12.55, paid by A.P.S. to cover court charges relating to conveyance of George Turner's land to Society.
  - George Turner in account with American Philos[ophical] Society, July 17, 1801; 6 3/4" x 8"; Turner, George, 1750-1843
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan. Statement of accounts, March 17, 1800 to July 17, 1801.
  - Extract from minutes., July 24, 1801; 7 5/8" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: B[urgess] Allison, Peter S. DuPonceau, R[obert] Patterson, J[oh]n Vaughan. Authorization of loan of $500 to Charles Willson Peale. Peale's receipt, dated July 27, 1801. on reverse.
  - C[harles] W[illson] Peale to Robert Patterson, July 24, 1801; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests loan of $500 from A.P.S. to help complete the skeleton of the mammoth.
  - Affidavit., July 25, 1801; 8 1/8" x 9 3/8"; Philadelphia. Recorder of deeds
    Sworn statement as to mortgages from Charles Willson Peale, in the city and county of Philadelphia, before July, 1801. [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Edward Fox, Recorder.
  - Report of committee on loan made to C.W. Peale, Aug. 21, 1801; 8x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S. Jn Vaughan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, P. 314.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the journal of Dr. Cutbush to and from the West Indies, containing an account of his observations upon the thermometer, September 18, 1801; 7 13/16" x 9 9/16"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan, R[obert] Patterson. To be preserved in the archives. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 314.
  - Bill to the American philosophical society for books purchased, formerly in Franklin's library, Sept. 23, 1801; 8x13; Dufief, N. G. (Nicolas Gouin), 1776?-1834
    Philadelphia, D.S.: N. Gouin Dufied and Jn. Vaughan. 2p.and end. See microfilm 95.
  - Le ministre d'economie politique de la republique Batave to the A.P.S., October 2, 1801; 9 1/4" x 15"; Batavian Republic
    La Haye, 1 p. and endorsement. Pr.D.S. (In French.) Donates the first three parts of Flora Batava to the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 321, March 19, 1802.
  - Bill, receipted, to the American philosophical society, Oct. 9, 1801; 12x8; Dufief, N. G. (Nicolas Gouin), 1776?-1834
    Philadelphia, D.S.: N. G. Dufief. 1p.and end. For books purchased of Dufief, formerly in Franklin's library. See microfilm 95.
  - Bill, receipted, to the American philosophical society for books purchased, formerly in Franklin's library, Oct. 31, 1801; 7x9; Dufief, N. G. (Nicolas Gouin), 1776?-1834
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.and end. See microfilm 95.
  - Letter to Francisco Peyrolon, Valencia, Nov. 5, 1801; 10x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, L.S.: John Redmond Coxe. 2p. Enc.wanting. Forwards diploma of membership. Thanks for publications of the royal society of Valencia. Forwards publications.
  - [American] Philosophical Society to Thomas Dobson, November 14, 1801; 4 7/8" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Tho[ma]s Dobson. Receipted bill for $.83, for paper and twine.
  - [American] Philosophical Society to William Y. Birch, November 26, 1801; 6 3/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Will[ia]m Y. Birch. Receipted bill for $2.25, for stationary.
  - Sam[ue]l F. Bradford to the American Philosophical Society, December 4, 1801; 4 7/8" x 7 7/8"; Bradford, Samuel F. (Samuel Fisher), 1776-1837
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S.: Asiatick Researches and Asiatick Poems of Sir William Jones.
  - List of papers not published, December 18, 1801; 8" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    (?)[Philadelphia,], 2 pp. D. Covers the period from September 19, 1800 to December 18, 1801.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Dec. 18, 1801; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p., end. Concerning forwarding of publications to Swedish members. Cf. Minutes, p.319.
  - Report of committee on furnishing the true time for Philadelphia, Dec. 18, 1801; 6x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.Patterson and R.Leslie, 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.319.
  - Am[erica]n Philosophical Society to Jane Aitken, Dr., Philadelphia, December 28, July 25, 1801, 1804; 8 1/8" x 13 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Jane Aitken, August 16, 1804. Statement of accounts totaling $183.18, "for sundry binding."
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s Jefferson, Dec. 29, 1801; 10x8; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Enc. wanting. (see Ms. Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no.38.) Encloses astronomical observations.
  - Letter to Rob[er]t Patterson, Dec. 29, 1801; 10x8; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820
    Lancaster A.L.S. 1p. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no.37.) Sends papers and has sent copies to Thomas Jefferson.
  - Josiah Quincy to John Vaughan, December 31, 1801; 7 7/8" x 9 1/8"; Quincy, Josiah
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. "The [Massachusetts] historical society will duly appreciate the attention of the [American] philosophical [Society] and will take care to signify their sense of it..."
  - Books in the library of the Am[erica]n Phil[osophical] Society, , 1801; 7 3/8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], ----, 1801. 1 p. and endorsement. D.
  - Particular account of Philosophical Transactions, [1801]; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Particular account of the Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London.
  - Massachusetts Historical Society to John Redman Coxe, Secretary of A.P.S., January 8, 1802; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsements. L.S.: John Eliot, Corresponding Secretary. Acknowledges receipt of four volumes of A.P.S. Transactions. Forwards Collections of Mass. Hist. Society, 7 vols.,
  - Books to be bound, left at [Robert] Aitkin's, Jan. 9, 1802; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.in hand of John Vaughan. 4p.,end. One book concerning B.Franklin.
  - [American] Philos[ophical] Society to William Y. Birch, January 11, 1802; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by William Y. Birch. Receipted bill for $4.12 1/2, for stationary.
  - The Insurance Company of North America to John Vaughan, January 11, 1802; 6 3/8" x 7 3/4"; Insurance Company of North America
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Cha[rle]s P. Heath. Receipt for $15.60, for insurance on Philosophical Hall and its contents for the year 1802.
  - Letter to John Vaughan and Charles W. Peale, Jan. 13, 1802; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, pres. U.S., 1743-1826
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges re-election to the presidency of the A.P.S. Bur. of rolls, v.6,471 - S.1,v.8,273 under date of Jan. 12.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, treasurer of A.P.S., January (?) 20, 1802; 8" x 10"; Casa Yrujo, Carlos Martínez de Yrujo y Tacón, marqués de, 1763-1824
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Acknowledges election to membership in the American philosophical society.
  - Astronomical observations made in Lancaster, Pa., Jan. 15, 1802; 10x7-1/2; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820
    [read] A.D. 7p.,end. (see Ms.comm. to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 1, nos. 39-40.) ----Letterpress copy. 6p. Cf. Minutes, p.320. Printed: Trans, o.s., VI, 61-69.
  - Linnean Society of London to J.R. Coxe, 1802 February 2; Linnean Society of London.
    The Secretary of the Linnean Society of London thanks J.R. Coxe of the American Philosophical Society for the gift of 5 volumes of the A.P.S. Transactions and sends them 6 volumes of the Linnean Society's Transactions.
  - Astronomical observations made at Lancaster, Feb. 13, 1802; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820
    A.D.S. 1p.and end.by R.P[atterson] and drawing of 2p.,end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 1, no.41.) Cf. Minutes, p.321. Printed: Trans.,n.s.,vol.I,93.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 18, 1802; 8x6-1/2; A Jolly Tar, Pseud.
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p.and end. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 31.) Concerning the ventilation of ships. Offered for the premium. Cf. Minutes, p.321.
  - Rem[brandt] Peale to Robert Patterson, February 19, 1802; 7 13/16" x 10 5/16"; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning his intended visit to Europe and the exhibition of the mammoth skeleton. Requests loan of certain bones of the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 321.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 12, 1802; 9x7-3/4; Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervindelijke Wijsbegeerte (Rotterdam, Netherlands)
    Rotterdam, A.L.S.: C.Dale, Sec. 2p.,add.and end. Sends five volumes of Transactions. Cf. Minutes, 325.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, 1802 March 17; 7 1/4" x 9 3/8"; France. L'institut national
    The French National Institute of Arts and Sciences, 2 pp. and endorsements. L.S. (In French.) Presents to the A.P.S.: "a Copy of its Transactions as far as published." [Paris, le 17 Ventrose l'an 10 de la Republique francaise]
  - Thomas B. Adams to Joseph Clay, jr., March 18, 1802; 8 1/8" x 10"; Adams, Thomas Boylston, 1772-1832
    Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Presents to A.P.S.: Defence of the American Constitution, by John Adams. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 321, March 19, 1802.
  - Letter to John Adams, Braintree, Mass., March 19, 1802; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Photo.of printed L.filled in in ms.S.: John Redman Coxe. 1p. Thanks for his publication, presented through his son. From original in Adams Papers,Mass.Hist Soc.,received from W.J.Be11,Jr.; Nov. 27, 1962.
  - Royal Society of Edinburgh to [the American Philosophical Society], March 19, 1802; 6 1/4" x 9 3/8"; Royal Society of Edinburgh
    Edinburgh, 1p. and endorsement. D.S.: Will[ia]m Wright. Acknowledges receipt of four volumes of A.P.S. Transactions.
  - William Y. Birch and Abr[aha]m Small to John Vaughan, April 1, 1802; 8" x 9 7/8"; Birch, William Young, 1764-1837
    Treasurer of A.P.S. Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Donates Russell's Ancient and Modern Europe, 7 vols., to the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 322, April 2, 1802.
  - Report of committee on [Benjamin] Shultz's paper on temperaments, April 2, 1802; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: B.S.Barton 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.322.
  - Report of committee on the publication of the fifth volume of the Transactions, April 2, 1802; 7x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Jn.Vaughan. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.322.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, 1802. April 3; L'Hommedieu, Ezra, 1734-1811
    Letter accompanying Resolutions of the Society for the Promotion of Agriculture, Arts & Manufactures
  - Sam[ue]l L. Mitchill to Adam Seybert, April 12, 1802; 8" x 9 15/16"; Mitchill, Samuel L. (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards to the A.P.S. a circular letter from the Agricultural Society of New York. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 323. Mentions Thomas Jefferson.
  - Letter to the president and members of the APS, April 15, 1802; 8-1/2x14; de Hüpsch, Baron
    Cologne, A.L.S. 7p., add., and end. In German. ----Copy. Translation. Concerning his anti-epileptic medicine. Inquires for details of yellow fever. Sends his "small writings" to the APS.
  - Baron de Hüpsch to [the American Philosophical Society], April 15, 1802; 7 7/8" x 12 7/8"; de Hüpsch, Baron.
    Cologne, 2 pp. and endorsement. L. Translation. Concerning his anti-epileptic medicine. Inquires for details of yellow fever. Sends his "small writings" to A.P.S.
  - Letter to the vice president of the A.P.S., April 16, 1802; 6 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    A.L.S. 3p. and end. Acknowledges for Dr. Samuel Fahlberg his election to membership, and presents in his name a map of a dangerous shoal near St. Bartholomew.
  - Letter to William Jones, American Philosophical Society.
    An order for meterological instruments.
  - John Brown to Thomas Jefferson, April 28, 1802; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Brown, John
    President of A.P.S., Boone County, Kentucky, 2 pp. A.L.S. Concerning bones found by Uriah Hardesty and forwarded to C. W. Peale. See Minutes, June 18, 1802, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 325.
  - American Philosophical Society to Jacob Johnson, April 29, 1802; 3 3/4" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Jacob Johnson. Receipted bill for $7.50, for a ream of colored paper.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the Société Hollandoise des Sciences, Haarlem, April 30, 1802; 10x8; Coxe, John Redman, 1773-1864
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S.: John Redman Coxe, Sec[retar]y. 1p. (from original in Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen.) Forwards first four volumes of Transaction and will send the fifth.
  - Royal Academy of Sciences and Belles-lettres of Prussia to the American Philosophical Society, May 3, 1802; 7 3/8" x 9"; Königlich Preussische Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, 2pp. and endorsements. L.S.: Merian, Secretary. (In French.) Concerning donation of Memoirs to the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 327, October 15, 1802.
  - together with a catalogue of the library., May 7, 1802; Massachusetts Historical Society
    See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 323,
  - C[harles] W[illson] Peale to [the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia], May 7, 1802; 8 1/16" x 10 5/16"; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Relative to removal of part of museum from Philosophical Hall to the State House. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 324.
  - Sam[uel] L. Mitchill to John Vaughan, May 28, 1802; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; Mitchill, Samuel L. (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., New York, 3 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. "The Agricultural Society of New York is not in possession of any of the Volumes of the A.P.S." A set would be "highly acceptable."
  - C. N. Buck and Company to J[oh]n Vaughan, May 29, 1802; 8 1/8" x 9 3/4"; Buck, C. N., and Company
    Secretary of A.P.S., Hamburg, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S.: C. N. Buck & Co. Have forwarded three sets of A. P. S. Transactions according to instructions.
  - B(enjamin) S(mith) Barton to John Vaughan, ----, May 31, 1802; 8" x 10"; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
    1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. List of books "which I am anxious to have from Italy."
  - John Brand to John Redman Coxe, June 1, 1802; 8" x 9 3/4"; Brand, John, 1744-1806
    Secretary to the A.P.S., London, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. The secretary of the Society of Antiquaries of London acknowledges receipt of the A.P.S. Transactions, I-IV. Forwards Archaeologia, I-XIII, to A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 327.
  - Letter to Rufus King, 1802 June 3; Society of Antiquaries of London
    In return for a copy of the A.P.S. Transactions, the Society of Antiquities of London sends the A.P.S. a complete set of their Archaeologia in 13 volumes.
  - Letter to William Vaughan, London, June 5, 1802; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.L.S. 2p.and add.: Samuel Vaughan & Son. Enc. Sends APS telescope to Wm.Jones for repairs for Andrew Ellicott's use in makining meteorological observations. Enc.is dated 1802 March 20: APS to W.Jones [should be 1801].
  - Sam[uel] Brown to John Vaughan, June 10, 1802; 8" x 10"; Brown, Samuel, 1749-1828
    Lexington, Kentucky, 5 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has sent vaccine to Natchez for William Dunbar. Concerning skull of ox kind sent to the A.P.S. 4p. only march 21, 1962
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 10, 1802; 10x8; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. Letterpress copy. Concerning communications from Ferrer, Livingston and Garnett.
  - Letter to the Secretary of Société Hollandoise des Sciences, Haarlem, June 18, 1802; 10x8; Coxe, John Redman, 1773-1864
    Philadelphia, Photo.of A.L.S.: John Redman Coxe, Sec[retar]y. 1p. (from original in Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen.) Forwards fifth volume of Transactions.
  - Letter to Benjamin Wells, 1802 June 28; unknown correspondent
    The author disagrees with Mr. Hamilton's opinion on the liability of collectors.
  - Giraud to the Society of Sciences at Philadelphia, July 2, 1802; 8 1/8" x 9 7/8"; Giraud-Duplessis, Pierre-Guillaume-Henri, 1754-1820
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Donates a copy of Grégoire's Apologie de Las Casas. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 326, August 20, 1802.
  - Jose Joaquin de Ferrer to John Vaughan, July 15, 1802; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; de Ferrer, Jose Joaquin
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In Spanish.) Concerning the donation of several dictionaries and grammars to the A.P.S. List appended.
  - Jose Joaquin de Ferrer to Benjamin Smith Barton, July 15, 1802; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; de Ferrer, Jose Joaquin
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. (In Spanish.) Concerning the donation of several dictionaries and grammars to the A.P.S. List appended.
  - R. Home to John Redman Coxe, July 20, 1802; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Home, Robert, 1752-1834
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Calcutta, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. The secretary of the Asiatic Society forwards seven volumes of their Researches to the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on James Hall's paper on an astronomical instrument, July 20, 1802; 6-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Joseph Clay and Jose Joaquin de Ferrer. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.328,
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society, July 23, 1802; 8" x 10"; Olsen, Peter Bleeker
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Acknowledges election to membership.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 24, 1802; 7" x 9"; Bacon, Josiah, 1785-1852
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Delivered books [A.P.S. Transactions] as directed. John Quincy Adams appointed secretary of the Academy of arts and sciences.
  - J(oh)n Vaughan to the Chev. de Yrujo, July 25, 1802; 8 1/4" x 10"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    ----, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards two copies of A.P.S. Transactions, V, to Yrujo, to be given to designated Spanish learned societies.
  - American Philosophical Society to James Humphreys, Dr., July 26, 1802; 6 1/2" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: James Humphreys. Receipted bill for $5.37 for printing and binding loan book.
  - C. N. Buck and Company to John Vaughan, July 31, 1802; 8 1/16" x 10 1/8"; Buck, C. N., and Company
    Hamburg, 1 p. Pr.D.S.: George Mclellan. Bill of lading for one case of books shipped by C. N. Buck & Co. to A.P.S. Enclosed in letter from C. N. Buck & Co. to John Vaughan, July 31, 1802.
  - C. N. Buck and Company to John Vaughan, July 31, 1802; 8" x 9 7/8"; Buck, C. N., and Company
    Hamburg, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. Notice of a case of books from the Royal Academy at Berlin shipped to A. P. S. on the brig Echo.
  - Royal Society of Sciences at Göttingen to the American Philosophical Society, August 1, 1802; 6" x 7"; Königliche Societät der Wissenschaften zu Göttingen
    Göttingen, 1 p. L.S.: Chr[istian] G. Heyne, Secretary of the Society. Sends eighteen volumes of Communications to the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 331, January 21, 1803.
  - Alex[ande]r Aubert to John Redman Coxe, August 4, 1802; 7 3/8" x 9 3/16"; Aubert, Alexander
    Secretary to the A.P.S., London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Informs A.P.S. that a case of books was sent to them on July 3, by the Society of Antiquaries of London.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 5, 1802; 8" x 10"; Maury, James, 1746-1840
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Delivered [Vol.5 of the A.P.S. Transactions] to the Literary and philosophical society at Manchester.
  - The American Philosophical Society to Tho[ma]s P. Jones, August 6, 1802; 7 1/8" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Tho[ma]s P. Jones. Receipted bill for $1.50, for repairing frame for lens.
  - John Dalton to John Redman Coxe, August 24, 1802; 8 1/4" x 10"; Dalton, John, 1766-1844
    Manchester, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. The secretary of the Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester acknowledges receipt of A.P.S. Transactions, IV and V, and transmits their Memoirs, IV and V.
  - Extract from will, September 2, 1802; 7 3/4" x 10 3/8"; Smith, Thomas P. (Thomas Peters), 1777 or 8-1802
    dated at sea, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S. Copy. Bequest of minerals to the A.P.S. See Minutes, May 6, 1803, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 337.
  - Extract from will [Copy], September 2, 1802
    Dated at sea, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S. Copy. Bequest of minerals to the A.P.S. See Minutes, May 6, 1803, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 337.
    Smith, Thomas P. (Thomas Peters), 1777 or 8-1802 -- Archives
  - Concerning some newly discovered islands and shoals in the Indian Ocean, Sept. 2, 1802; 10-1/2x8; Thomas,
    D. 2p.and end. and end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 1, no. 15.) Cf. Minutes, pp.336, 339.
  - Letter to J.R. Coxe, secretary of the A.P.S., Sept. 6, 1802; 7 1/4" x 9"; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    London, A.L.S: J.P. Auriol, secretary. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges Vol.5 of A.P.S.Transactions.
  - John Timaeur to J[ohn] R[edman] Coxe, Secretary to the A.P.S., September 19, 1802; 8" x 9 3/4"; Timaeur, John
    Lüneburg, 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Is forwarding a box of Göttingen Transactions to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Redmond Coxe, Philadelphia, Sept. 23, 1802; 9x7-1/2; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, A.L.S.: Merian. 1p.and translation and add.,end. In french. Thanks for publications and forwards their publications.
  - McCara and Fridge to John Vaughan, October 18, 1802; 8" x 9 3/4"; McCara and Fridge
    Alexandria, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.N.S. Note covering acknowledgment of "Societys of Edinburgh that they had recd Volumes."
  - Council of the Interior of the Batavian Republic to the American Philosophical Society, October 21, 1802; 9" x 14 7/8"; Batavian Republic
    Hague, 2 pp. L.S.: Wenckebach. Suggests that the A.P.S. cooperate with the Batavian republic in an exchange of plants and seeds. See: A.P.S., Resolution, July 15, 1803.
  - Le ministre d'economie politique de la republique Batave to the A.P.S., October 21, 1802; 7 11/16" x 12 3/8"; Batavian Republic
    La Haye, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. (In French.) Donates cahiers 4-6 of Flora Batava to the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 339-340.